<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DARKNAVY</title>
    <link>https://www.darknavy.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DARKNAVY</description>
    <image>
      <title>DARKNAVY</title>
      <url>https://www.darknavy.org/images/white_logo.png</url>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/images/white_logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 15:40:57 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.darknavy.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AVSS Report: System Security Adversarial Capability Preliminary Evaluation of iOS, Android, and HarmonyOS - Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/avss_report_kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 15:40:57 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/avss_report_kernel/</guid>
      <description>As consumers, when faced with five different brands and models of smartphones or ten different smart cars, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for us to determine which one can effectively prevent our privacy from being stolen or maliciously accessed, such as our location or even hearing our conversations inside the car.
Even as ordinary consumers, we currently have no way of knowing. As technology professionals who have long studied in APT(Advanced Persistent Threat) attacks, we understand that these devices can ultimately be compromised in the face of advanced persistent attacks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening the Shield: MTE in Heap Allocators</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/strengthening_the_shield_mte_in_memory_allocators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 16:19:13 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/strengthening_the_shield_mte_in_memory_allocators/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In 2018, with the release of ARMv8.5-A, a brand new chip security feature MTE (Memory Tagging Extensions) emerged. Five years later, in 2023, the first smartphone to support this feature was released — Google Pixel 8 — marking the official entry of MTE into the consumer market. Although this feature is not yet enabled by default, developers can turn it on themselves for testing.
As a powerful defense against memory corruption, there has not yet been a comprehensive analysis of MTE&amp;rsquo;s defensive boundaries, capabilities, and its impact on performance on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>填补盾牌的裂缝：堆分配器中的MTE</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/blog_cn/strengthening_the_shield_mte_in_memory_allocators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 16:14:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/blog_cn/strengthening_the_shield_mte_in_memory_allocators/</guid>
      <description>前言 2018年，随着ARMv8.5-A的发布，一个全新的芯片安全特性MTE(Memory Tagging Extensions) 横空出世。时隔五年后的2023年，市场上第一款支持此特性的手机发布 —— Google Pixel 8，宣告着MTE正式走入了消费者群体。虽然该特性在手机上还未默认启用，但开发者可以自行开启体验。
MTE作为一个强大的内存破坏防御手段，对于它的防御边界、防御能力，和它对性能的影响，目前网上还未有对其全面的分析。此前，Google Project Zero发表了一系列关于MTE的文章，其聚焦于较为底层的MTE安全性。然而MTE对于真实的软件安全性究竟有多大的影响仍是个未解之谜。想要讨论这个话题，各大堆分配器是一个很好的切入点。堆上的内存破坏问题已经逐渐成为二进制漏洞中的主流类型，参考MSRC于CppCon2019的议题内容：
通常普通开发者并不会直接使用MTE相关的汇编指令，而是依靠堆分配器自带的MTE支持间接使用，堆分配器就像盾牌一样，扛起了保护软件的任务。MTE提供了细颗粒管控内存的基础支持，如何基于硬件MTE能力实现高级安全功能的重任，留给了软件开发者。开源社区主流堆分配器积极响应，实现了基于MTE特性的安全增强，提高了堆空间的内存安全性。
本文将以MTE的三个主要玩家：Chrome中的PartitionAlloc、Glibc中的Ptmalloc、Android中的Scudo为目标，对其中MTE相关的实现分别进行讨论，并对它们进行对比。我们在研究中发现了PartitionAlloc中实现的问题，并将此问题报告给了Google，得到了Chrome团队的确认。
MTE概述 已了解MTE原理的读者可跳过此章节。
MTE利用ARMv8的TBI (Top-Byte Ignore) 特性，使用指针的高4 bits存储tag，在每个进程中有一段专用的内存用于存储tag。当为内存指定了某个tag后，程序必须带上正确的tag访问内存，若tag错误，程序抛出错误信号SIGSEGV，如下图所示：
指令集提供了系列指令来操作tag，此处举例说明MTE的基本用法：
; x0 is a pointer irg x1, x0 stg x1, [x1] ldr x0, [x1] IRG (Insert Random Tag) 指令为指针x0生成一个随机tag，将结果保存至x1中。 STG (Store Allocation Tag) 指令将tag应用至内存中，生效的长度取决于颗粒度，一般为16字节。 LDR (Load Register) 使用带有tag的指针读取内存。 可以看到指令集中提供了底层的支持，但各个指令的使用有很大的自由度，MTE具体如何使用，很大程度上仍然取决于软件开发者。
Allocator Chrome - PartitionAlloc 分配 PartitionAlloc中的分配可以大致分为三种情况：
从ThreadCache中分配，不变动tag直接返回。 从空闲的SlotSpan中分配，不变动tag直接返回。 若以上两种情况均不满足，分配一个新的SlotSpan，对其中所有空闲的堆块打上随机的tag if (PA_LIKELY(use_tagging)) { // Ensure the MTE-tag of the memory pointed by other provisioned slot is // unguessable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the libwebp Vulnerability, Part 2: Diving into Chrome Blink</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/blog_cn/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:10:29 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/blog_cn/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_2/</guid>
      <description>前言 当我们把这样一个在三方库中的漏洞放到真实的环境中再看时，会发现漏洞所处的环境往往有很多复杂的变量，想要利用这个漏洞并非想象般那么容易。
我们所已知的信息有：
我们溢出的变量huffman_tables，大小为0x2f28 该堆块在renderer的ThreadPool中分配，而大多数对象在主线程中分配 我们可以以8字节倍数的offset，写入一个部分可控的4字节int Chrome中不同大小的堆块被存储在不同的bucket当中，不同大小的对象因为这个机制被安全地隔离开。通常来说，在chrome中的堆利用需要找到同样大小的对象进行布局，再通过UAF或是OOB篡改其他的对象，从而造成信息泄露或者控制流劫持。接下来我们会分享我们所发现的对象，同时试图去绕过这个机制。
信息泄露 寻找对象 我们首先想要寻找的是一个合适的对象能够被OOB所改写，由于我们的越界写并不能很好地控制值，所以写指针基本被排除，最好的情况是能够改掉类似length这样的字段，对于值没有精确的要求，但是能够引发进一步更好利用的内存问题。
HuffmanCode在libwebp中是用malloc分配的，在chrome中实际是被PartitionAlloc最终接管分配。在renderer中一共有四个partition，LayoutObject partition, Buffer partition, ArrayBuffer partition, FastMalloc partition。FastMalloc实际上最终调用的就是malloc，因此我们想要找的对象可以用FastMalloc来分配。
我们首先用了Man Yue Mo在博客中提到的codeql查询，由于溢出在0x3000的bucket当中，可以选择的对象大小范围为0x2800 - 0x3000。但非常遗憾的是，查询结果为空，这个size下的对象几乎完全不存在。另一个思路是用溢出对象本身，但是这个对象被改掉后不会产生特别的破坏效果，libwebp中也没有其他好的候选对象。到了这里似乎令人觉得有些绝望，利用的第一步就被卡住了。
那么我们还有什么思路呢，一个想法是使用可变长的对象，如Man Yue Mo提到过的AudioArray，但是这个对象是纯数据，被改掉也没有用。查看所有FastMalloc的调用，最终我们发现了这个对象
class CORE_EXPORT CSSVariableData : public RefCounted&amp;lt;CSSVariableData&amp;gt; { USING_FAST_MALLOC(CSSVariableData); 此对象的大小为动态的
wtf_size_t bytes_needed = sizeof(CSSVariableData) + (original_text.Is8Bit() ? original_text.length() : 2 * original_text.length()); // ... snip ... void* buf = WTF::Partitions::FastMalloc( bytes_needed, WTF::GetStringWithTypeName&amp;lt;CSSVariableData&amp;gt;()); 该对象代表了CSS中的变量，可以通过以下方式来定义
element { foo: var(--my-var, bar); } blink会根据CSS变量的内容动态分配CSSVariableData的内存。还有一个好消息是，JavaScript中也可以便捷地操作CSS变量。
// add a CSS variable element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the libwebp Vulnerability, Part 1: Playing with Huffman Code</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/blog_cn/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:10:24 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/blog_cn/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_1/</guid>
      <description>漏洞定位 在初始的漏洞分析阶段，由于缺少现成的PoC或详细分析报告，我们首先尝试阅读并理解webmproject/libwebp上游仓库针对CVE-2023-4863的修复代码。然而，WebM Project官方的修补过程相对复杂，这使得我们难以精确地锁定漏洞的原始触发点。
于是，我们将目光转向了Apple对CVE-2023-41064的官方补丁，并使用BinDiff对更新前后的ImageIO组件进行了对比。我们注意到Apple的补丁代码变更相对较少，易于理解，并且非常“简单粗暴”:
简而言之，Apple的修复方案是在WebP解码器中增加了一项检查：如果在构建霍夫曼编码表 (Huffman Table) 时越界，就会直接返回错误，而不是继续解码。
diff --git a/src/dec/vp8l_dec.c b/src/dec/vp8l_dec.c index 45012162..06b142bc 100644 --- a/src/dec/vp8l_dec.c +++ b/src/dec/vp8l_dec.c @@ -438,6 +438,7 @@ static int ReadHuffmanCodes(VP8LDecoder* const dec, int xsize, int ysize, goto Error; } + bound = &amp;amp;huffman_tables[num_htree_groups * table_size]; huffman_table = huffman_tables; for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; num_htree_groups_max; ++i) { // If the index &amp;#34;i&amp;#34; is unused in the Huffman image, just make sure the diff --git a/src/utils/huffman_utils.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the libwebp Vulnerability, Part 2: Diving into Chrome Blink</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:10:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When we examine a third-party library vulnerability in a real environment, we often encounter numerous complex variables that exist within the vulnerability&amp;rsquo;s context. Exploiting such a vulnerability is not as easy as one might imagine.
Here is the information we know:
The overflowed variable huffman_tables, has a size of 0x2f28. The heap chunk is allocated in the renderer&amp;rsquo;s ThreadPool, while most objects are allocated in the main thread. We can write a partially controlled 4-byte integer with an offset that is a multiple of 8 bytes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the libwebp Vulnerability, Part 1: Playing with Huffman Code</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:10:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/blog/exploiting_the_libwebp_vulnerability_part_1/</guid>
      <description>Vulnerability Localization In the initial phase of vulnerability analysis, due to the absence of readily available PoCs or detailed analysis reports, we first attempted to read and understand the patch code for CVE-2023-4863 in the upstream repository of webmproject/libwebp. However, the WebM Project&amp;rsquo;s official patch was relatively complex, making it difficult for us to accurately pinpoint the root cause of the vulnerability.
Thus, we turned our attention to Apple&amp;rsquo;s official patch for CVE-2023-41064, and performed a comparison of the ImageIO framework before and after the update using BinDiff.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.darknavy.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 17:11:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.darknavy.org/about/</guid>
      <description>We are DARKNAVY, an independent and free-spirited security research team and service provider. We have established AVSS (Adversarial Vulnerability Scoring System) to evaluate vulnerabilities and the effectiveness of system mitigation mechanisms in real adversarial environments.
Over the past 20 years, we have been at the forefront of cybersecurity research and application, winning multiple world championships. We have also established GEEKCON, a unique and top-class security geek competition, and responsibly disclosed over 1000 severe vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
